BLUE RAMAILA ABAD

San Jose, CA 95127

Phone: (408) 8349225 | Email: bibo_1011@yahoo.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/blue-ramaila-abad/ | Portfolio: bibo1011.github.io/react-blue-ramaila-abad/

GitHub: github.com/bibo1011

SUMMARY

Experienced electro-mechanic technician with a complex knowledge on space systems to deliver unparalleled outlook to the rapidly evolving mobile technology. Highly adaptable with passion on learning new technologies to develop products that fulfills end-user satisfaction.

EXPERIENCE

Lockheed Martin Space - Sunnyvale, CA

Title: Senior Vehicle Test Operation Technician; October 2017- Present

- Perform installation and integration of electrical and mechanical components
- Uses a variety of basic hand tools such as for stripping and crimping wires, soldering equipment and mechanical torque
- Perform electrical and mechanical support for ambient and environmental tests
- Perform instrument installation and operate electrical testing equipment, pneumatic systems testing, flight hardware deployments, and manual testing.
- Install breakout boxes, breakout cables, and instrumentation to troubleshoot test set-ups and hardware involved in tests
- Work closely with Certified Test Conductors/Floor Engineers for daily tasks and goals
- Interpret assembly drawings and specifications from Creo Viewer and uses Automation Framework for reading procedures
- Support vehicle launch campaigns at launch bases
- Ability to read and interpret assembly drawings, specifications and schematics and follow work instructions and test procedures for the purpose of fabrication, assembly and test
- Conducted physical and electrical tests using scientific measuring equipment
- Monitored and controlled tests performed on units and equipment, ensuring objectivity and compliance to the procedure
- Ensured electrical and mechanical components are installed and operating properly as part of quality assurance responsibility

Space Systems/Loral, (SSL/MDA)- Palo Alto, CA

Title: Quality Control Inspector (Spacecraft and Sub-assembly Level); December 2013- July 2017

- Prevented quality problems by recommending improvements and/or changes to the manufacturing/inspection process to correct potential deficiencies.
- Provided close support to manufacturing areas in order to rapidly recognize quality problems that do arise.
- Assisted in identifying the potential causes of quality problems and in the implementation of corrective actions.
- Closely follow test and inspection procedures for products in order to administer various phases of the quality assurance program for a major production area.
- Assisted in making recommendations regarding any changes that are not conforming to quality standards.
- Performed ID&D inspection of the unit according to specific instruction, procedure and ICD drawing.
- Monitored, witness/surveillance and control tests performed on units and equipment, assuring objectivity and compliance to
- Log or update inspection transaction and data on QC database.
- Created a Non-Conformance Report for a unit or event that does not comply or out of tolerance according to the latest release of procedure and work instruction.
- Worked on PLM and MRP system database such as Siemens Teamcenter, Parametric Creo Viewer, AIMS and Flexsys

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- **Engineering Drawing Interpretation**
- **Document Control**
- **Quality Compliance**
- **Inventory Management**
- Logistic Functions
- Forklift Operation
- Mechanical Assembly
- **Electrical Testing**
- Microscope Use

- HTML/CSS
- Github
- Javascript
- jQuery
- React
- **Express**
- Node
- SQL
- Mongodb

PROJECTS

Plenty of Brew | github.com/bibo1011/simple-mrp | simple-mrp-hameed1239.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Search application for local breweries around the city. Results include a link to their website, their location and contact number of the brewery.
- Role: Lead, Front-end and Back-end
- Tools: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, JQuery, API

Simple MRP | github.com/bibo1011/simple-mrp | simple-mrp-hameed1239.herokuapp.com/

- Contactless virtual train ticket. Online purchasing app and wallet for train tickets.
- Role: Back-end
- Tools: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Materialize, Font Awesome, Express, Handlebars, MySQL, Heroku, Insomnia Core, Bcrypt

TransferCard | github.com/itsrheine/transferCard | transfercard.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Contactless virtual train ticket. Online purchasing app and wallet for train tickets.
- Role: Back-end
- Tools: HTML/CSS Javascript, MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js, GraphQL, Mongoose, Heroku, Material-ui/Core, Stripe, API, Styled-Components,

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Highest Educational Attainment:

- Full Stack Coding Bootcamp, University of California, Berkeley, 2021 Berkeley, California
- Four Years of Undergraduate Study Toward a BS in Civil Engineering U.S. GPA Credential Evaluation Certificate
 Mapua Institute of Technology, 2000-2004
 Manila, Philippines
- High School, University of Santo Tomas, 2000 Manila, Philippines

Training:

- PPE (Personal Protective Equipment)
- Hazmat
- Kaizen/Lean/5S
- ISO Standard Cleanroom
- Export Control
- Contamination Control
- Adhesive and Thermal Compound Bonding
- NASA Hand Solder
- NASA Cable and Harness
- Forklift and Personal Aerial Lift Device

Clearance:

- U.S. Department of Justice ATF Clearance Federal Explosives License/Permit: 9-CA-085-20-9B-01864
- U.S. Department of Defense Security Clearance TS/SCI Clearance

OTHER ORGANIZATION

- San Leandro Lodge No. 113, F & AM
- Willow Glen Fraternity No. 399, F & AM
- San Jose York Rite & Knights Templar